Finding Aid for Pioneer Band Association records, 1912-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Pioneer Band Association records
1912-2011
1960s-2011
Pioneer Band Association. Michigan Historical Collections staff
2012066 Bp 2
8 linear feet in 10 boxes
1 oversize volumes
1 tubes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records of the organization were donated in December 2011. (Donor no. 10684 )
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Pioneer Band Association was established to preserve the history of the school bands of Ann Arbor. Michigan.
The archives of the Pioneer Band Association document the history of the bands of Ann Arbor High School. Although Ann Arbor at this writing in 2012 has three high schools, these files primarily concern the Pioneer High School Band. The materials have been arranged into the following series: Class Files, People Files, Subject Files, Band Notes and related material, Visual Materials, Sound Recordings, Digital Materials, and Miscellaneous. Even though the records date from 1912, the bulk of the collection dates from the late 1960s. Much of the earlier material is copied from yearbooks and various archival resources. The People series includes research notes about different band members and notes from interviews with individuals who participated with the band in some capacity.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor High School (Mich.)--Bands.Bands.; Pioneer Band Association.; Pioneer High School (Ann Arbor, Mich.)--Bands.Bands.; Bands (Music)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; School music--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
CD-ROMs.; Compact discs.; DVDs.; Photographs.
- Class files
  - 1912-1970, 50 folders (Box 1)
  - Chicago, 1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970-1996, 27 folders (Box 1)
  - Auction/Dance, 1996 (Box 1)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Band Dance/Silent Auction, 1997 (Box 1)
  - 1997-1999, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Band Dance/Auction, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Family Dance Parent Coordinator, 1999 (Box 1)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Boston Tour, April, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Request for FTE, 2000 (Box 1)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - China Trip, 2001 (Box 1)
  - 2001-2002, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bus Lines, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Albritton, Departure, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Chicago Trip, Spring, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Leach, David, 2002 (Box 1)
  - 2002-2003, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Uniforms, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - Website, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - Band Camp, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Marine, 2003 (Box 2)
  - 2003-2006, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Yearbook, 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - 2006-2007 (Box 2)
  - Photos, 2007 (Box 2)
  - 2007-2010, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - 2010-2011 (Box 3)
  - , Class of, 2014 (Box 3)
  - Centennial Project, circa 2006 (Box 3)
- People files
  - Addison, Terri, 2/17/2006 (Box 3)
  - Albritton, Robert (Box 3)
  - Albritton, Robert Notes, Interview, July 19, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Baird, Bob, Interview, 3/16/2009 (Box 3)
  - Ballin, Tony (Box 3)
  - Becher, Eric, Interview, 7/14/2006 (Box 3)
  - Begian, Harry (Box 3)
  - Bordo, Victor (Box 3)
  - Bordo, Victor, collection (Box 3)
  - Bordo, Victor, Notes, Interview, August 22, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Cartwright, Lorin, Interview, November 3, 2008 (Box 3)
  - Champion, William (Box 3)
  - Champion, Edward, Notes, Interview, 1/23/2007 (Box 3)
  - Clague, Hannah (Box 3)
  - Collins, Verne (Box 3)
  - Cotton, Don (Box 3)
  - Cowan, Bruce, 7/29/2006 (Box 3)
  - Dittmar, Larry, Interview, May 5, 2010 (Box 3)
  - Doss, Dorothy, 2/1/2009 (Box 3)
  - Doss, Dorothy, materials (Box 3)
  - Downing, Edward (Box 3)
  - Falcone, Nicholas (Box 3)
  - Ferrick, Susan Lunk, collection (Box 3)
  - Frye, Djina, Notes, Interview, 1/9/2007 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Groves, Bill, Notes, Interview, 1/29/2007 (Box 3)
  - Holz, Emil (Box 3)
  - Howland, Samantha (Box 3)
  - Jacobi, Roger (Box 3)
  - Jacobi, Roger, Notes, Interview, May 27-28, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Jenkins, John (Box 3)
  - Kassof, Katia (Box 3)
  - Kausch, Eve Marie (Box 3)
  - Kemble, Jordain (Box 3)
  - Larkins, Charles, Interview, August 27, 2007 (Box 3)
  - Lavalle, Paul (Box 3)
  - Leach, David A. (Box 3)
  - Long, Dan, Notes, Interview, November 23, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Lynn, Zachary (Box 3)
  - Maddy, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Martino, Michael (Box 3)
  - Mazur, Myles A. (Box 3)
  - Meretta, Leonard (Box 3)
  - Moore, Earl (Box 3)
  - Morningstar, Nathan (Box 3)
  - Morris, Jack, Notes, Interview, July 13, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Pernecky, Grace (Box 3)
  - Pratt, Robert (Box 3)
  - Revelli, William (Box 3)
  - Rickman, Emmajane (Box 3)
  - Roth, Clarence (Box 3)
  - Roth, Tom, collection, December 2005 (Box 3)
  - Roth, Tom, Notes, Interview, 12/8/2005 (Box 3)
  - Schrodt, Gordon (Box 3)
  - Silfies, E. Rollin (Box 3)
  - Teeter, Ryan (Box 3)
  - Terrell, Stephanie (Box 3)
  - Torres, Maria (Box 3)
  - Tyra, Thomas (Box 3)
  - Visnick, Tanner (Box 3)
  - Wang, Charles (Box 3)
  - Waring, Nancy (Box 3)
  - Wattles, Isabel (Box 3)
  - Whitwell, John (Box 3)
  - Wines, Levi D. (Box 3)
  - Yates, Charles M. (Box 3)
- Subject files
  - Alumni Biographical Information (Box 3)
  - Alumni Rosters (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Area Alliance for Performing Arts Education (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor High School Building
    - 1856-1904 (Box 3)
    - 1907-1956 (Box 3)
    - 1956-circa 2010 (Box 3)
    - Frieze demolition (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor High School March (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor News Articles (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Observer Articles (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Public Schools Educational Foundation (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Public Schools Music Meetings (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Symphony Orchestra (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Area Community Foundation Annual Reports/Funds (Box 3)
  - Balas Bldg. Music Files, Summer 2005 (Box 3)
  - Band Camp (Box 3)
  - Band Financial Task Force (Box 3)
  - Bands in Review (1953 on) (Box 3)
  - Blue Lake Fine Arts Camp (Box 3)
  - Books, Notes from Reading (Box 3)
  - Bordo, Vic, Roast, 6/27/2003 (Box 3)
  - Chicago Mid-West, 1969; 2/3/2005 (Box 3)
  - Core Curriculum (Box 3)
  - Directors/Asst. Directors, Chronology (Box 3)
  - First Article, 1914-2004 (Box 3)
  - Food (Box 3)
  - Form 990, 1994-1999; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Hill Auditorium (Box 3)
  - Interlochen (Box 3)
  - Interlochen Photo Archive, Research-Summer, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Long, Dan, Fund (Box 3)
  - Michigan Marching Band (Box 3)
  - Michigan Youth Band (Box 3)
  - Midwest Clinic (Box 3)
  - Michigan School Band and Orchestra Association (Box 4)
  - Music Associations (Box 4)
  - Music & Athletics (Box 4)
  - Music Programs Ann Arbor Pioneer High School (Box 4)
  - New Musical Terms (Box 4)
  - Old Ann Arbor High Building (Box 4)
  - Omega Wish List (Box 4)
  - Orchestra, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Picnic Pops (Box 4)
  - Pioneer Band Association
    - Meeting Agendas/Minutes (Box 4)
    - Notes Newsletter (Box 4)
  - Pioneer Band Room Files (Box 4)
  - Pops (Box 4)
  - Program Border (Box 4)
  - Quibley-Young, M.J. Fund (Box 4)
  - Reflections in Excellence (Box 4)
  - Revelli Foundation (Box 4)
  - Revelli Report (Box 4)
  - Shar Music (Box 4)
  - Skyline High School (Box 4)
  - Summer Research, Angelina Hurst, 2007 (Box 4)
  - University of Maryland (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan (Box 4)
- Band Notes and related material
  - Band Notes, 1970-1975 (Box 4)
  - Band Notes, Minutes, 1975-1988 (Box 4)
  - Band Notes, Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
  - Band Notes, Minutes, 1985-1992 (Box 4)
  - Band Notes, Minutes, 1991-2001 (Box 4)
  - Band Notes, Minutes, 2000-2003 (Box 4)
  - Band Wagon, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Bus Information (Box 4)
  - Member Participation Forms, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - President's Records, Association By-laws, 1977-1989 (Box 5)
  - Projects Chairperson, Miscellaneous Records, 1968-1988 (Box 5)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Undated, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Undated, Portraits of Band Directors (Box 5)
    - 1906-1963 (Box 5)
    - 1910s (Box 5)
    - 1920s (Box 5)
    - 1930s (Box 5)
    - 1940s (Box 5)
    - 1950s (Box 5)
    - 1960s (Box 5)
    - 1970s (Box 5)
    - 1974 (Box 5)
    - 1980s (Box 5)
    - 1994 (Box 5)
    - 1997 (Box 5)
    - 1998 (Box 5)
    - 2000s (Box 5)
    - 2005 (Box 5)
    - 2006 (Box 5)
    - Music, various, undated (Box 6)
    - Music, Purple and White, undated (Box 6)
    - The Revelli Years, 1935-1971 (Box 6)
    - Marching Band Fundamentals, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
    - Pioneer Bands, Program, December 15, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Pioneer Symphony Bands, 42nd Annual Midwestern Conference on School Vocal and Instrumental Music, January 24, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Paula's Place coupon, 2006 (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Observer, May and June 2006; 2 issues (Box 6)
    - Band Photo, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
    - Sherman House, Chicago, December 17, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Conrad Hilton, Chicago, December 19, 1980 (Box 7)
    - 42nd Annual Midwestern Music Conference, Symphony, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
    - Festivals of Music, Toronto, 1988; 2 prints (Box 7)
    - Festivals of Music, Virginia Beach, 1990; 2 prints (Box 7)
    - Fiesta-Val, Myrtle Beach, 1992; 3 prints (Box 7)
    - Fiesta-Val, Virginia Beach, 1994; 3 prints (Box 7)
    - Concert, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Jazz, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Symphony, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Varsity, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Music Festivals, Toronto, 1996; 3 prints (Box 8)
    - Festivals of Music, New York, 1998; 3 prints (Box 8)
    - Heritage Festivals, Chicago, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Slides (Box 9)
    - 1968 (Box 9)
    - 1989, 7 boxes (Box 9)
    - 1992, 7 boxes (Box 9)
    - 1993, 8 boxes (Box 9)
    - 1994, 8 boxes (Box 9)
    - 1995, 7 boxes (Box 9)
  - Videotapes
    - Mr. A. Interlochen (Box 9)
    - Robert Albritton Celebration June 14th Pioneer High School, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Unlabeled (Box 9)
- Sound Recordings
  - Reel-to-reel tapes
    - Drum Cadences, undated; 5 in. (Box 10)
    - #15, undated; 7 in. (Box 10)
    - PHS Bands interview, 7 in. (Box 10)
      (inc master CD)
  - Stenorette tapes
    - Hood, 8/13/1964; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Green, 9/14/1964; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Cowen, 11/4/1964; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Platt, 11/9/1964; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Nelson, 4/5/1965; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Jacoby, 5/3/1965; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Duff, 5/6/1965; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Holz, 8/11/1965; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Hood, Reel 2, 8/1969; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Jacoby, tail out, undated; 3 in. (Box 10)
    - Unlabeled, undated; 3 in. (Box 10)
  - Audiocassettes
    - Victor Bordo (1 & 2), 8/22/2003 (Box 10)
    - Robert Albritton, 7/19/2004; 2 tapes (Box 10)
    - Dan Long, 11/23/2004; 2 tapes (Box 10)
    - Roger Jacobi, 5/27/2005 (Box 10)
    - Roger Jacobi, 5/28/2005 (Box 10)
    - Jack Morris (1 & 2), 7/13/2005 (Box 10)
    - Tom Roth (1 & 2), 12/8/2005 (Box 10)
    - Ted Heusel, 1/23/2006 (Box 10)
    - Eric Becher, 7/14/2006 (Box 10)
    - Bruce Cowan, 7/29/2006 (Box 10)
    - Djina Frye, 1/9/2007 (Box 10)
    - Edward Champion, 1/23/2007 (Box 10)
    - Bill Groves, 1/29/2007 (Box 10)
    - Charles Larkins, 8/27/2007 (Box 10)
    - Lorin Cartwright, 11/3/2008 (Box 10)
    - Dorothy Doss, 2/1/2009 (Box 10)
    - Bob Baird, 3/16/2009 (Box 10)
    - Larry Dittmar, 5/5/2010 (Box 10)
  - Phonograph records
    - King and I, undated (Box 1)
    - Pioneer High School A Cappella Choirs, Symphony, undated (Box 1)
    - Concerto Concert Symphony Orchestra, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Forsythe Junior High School, Highlights of, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Midwest National Band and Orchestra Clinic, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Pioneer High School Symphony, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Pioneer High School Symphony, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Youth for Understanding, Chorale & String Ensemble, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Pioneer High School Symphony, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Pioneer High School Symphony, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
- Digital Materials
  - Audio compact discs
    - Pioneer Band Shows, 1974-1997 (Box 10)
    - Mr. A. Speech, MOTS, & Blue Shades, 2002 (Box 10)
    - Winter Recital & Concert, February 2, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Celebration Concert 2006 National Grammy Signature School Award, May 30, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Winter Recital & Concert, February 1, 2007; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 10)
  - DVDs
    - Albritton, Robert Celebration, June 14, 2002; 5 optical disks DVDs (Box 10)
    - Jazz Band at the Firefly Club, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Winter Concert, February 7, 2008 (Box 10)
    - Dan Long Presentation, 3/4/2009 (Box 10)
    - B.I.R., March 20, 2010 (Box 10)
    - William Champion Home Movies (Box 10)
    - Happy Birthday Pioneer (Box 10)
    - Clarence Roth, Home Movies, Band Camp (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Directory Project, 12/2004 (Box 10)
    - Banquet, The Year In Review, May 8, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Banquet Presentation, 2006-2007 (Box 10)
    - Austria Tour, PBA Forms, Files, etc., 2006; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 10)
    - Centennial Project Insert, Winter Concert, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Centennial Project Alumni Database, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Centennial Project, Files, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Handbook, 2006-2007 (Box 10)
    - Powerpoint Presentation, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Senior book, Students, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Alumni Directory, 2007 (Box 10)
    - John Clifford Files (Box 10)
    - Master Files, 2 optical disks CDs (Box 10)
    - PTSO (Box 10)
    - Uniform Files (Box 10)
    - Website Banner Files (Box 10)
  - Photographs
    - 1938-1940 (Box 10)
    - Interlochen, MI, 1965 (Box 10)
    - China, from Judy Nies, 2001 (Box 10)
    - Band Photos, Camp, Picnic Pops, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
    - Picnic, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Band Photos, Stout, 2005-2006 (Box 10)
    - Band Photos, 2005-2006 (Box 10)
    - Band Photos, 5/24/2005 (Box 10)
    - Austria Tour Photos, David Michaels, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Europe, Gail's Photos, 2006; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 10)
    - Europe, Lauren's photos, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Europe, Mike's photos, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Senior Pictures, Class of, 2006 (Box 10)
    - William Champion Photos, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Senior Pictures, Class of, 2007 (Box 10)
    - Ranthony, Fall 2008 (Box 10)
    - Robert Albritton photos, 2009 (Box 10)
    - Bands in Review, AA News, Lon Horodel, 2009 (Box 10)
    - AAHS Band, Maddy, 1/27/2010 (Box 10)
    - Robert Albritton photos (Box 10)
    - Robert Albritton JPG & TIF (Box 10)
    - Camp photos, National Music, Interlochen, Post (Box 10)
    - Falcone Files, 2 and other MMB photos (Box 10)
    - John Shultz Photography (Box 10)
    - Slottow, photos (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  - Musical score for Band, Commissioned for Clarence Roth for the, 1961 (Volume 1)
  - Band posters, 3 posters (Tube 1)